

BSC COMPUTER SCIENCE GRADUATE · ENGLISH & PORTUGUESE

Louth · Ireland

🛮 (+353) 0838563877 | 💌 itsdanlopes@gmail.com | 🖸 dloppes | 🛅 daniel-lopes-soares-b35109110 | Graduation Award: Merit Grade 1

Summary_

Byron Pulsifer once said: "To adapt is to move ahead." As Brazilian that has left my roots and reside in Ireland for the past 5 years I live by this motto.

More than 15 years of experience in the business industry has led me to be driven, focused, business oriented and data driven. Communicating with a multinational client, producing daily reports, analysing data, negotiating debts and helping the company I worked for expand more than 15% its growth in a month and 100% in a year are some of my accomplishments.

Whether it is working on group project in College leading a team of 4 people, talking to an audience in church of 500 or being on TV/Radio due to my journalism course I take pride in communicating in the most effective way and engaging with my audience.

I make it my mission to have goals and set the targets to get where I want to be. Challenges do not discourage me. I love overcoming difficult situations and it is even more gratifying when I can bring other fellow colleagues along with me on the journey. Teamwork is essential in my conception if you want to get farther quicker.

Enjoying myself is extremely important to me too, when I am not working or studying, you can find me out exploring the world with my fiancee, working out.

Education

CCT COLLEGE Dublin, Ireland

BSc of Information Technology (Award: Merit Grade 1)

Sep. 2018 - Jun. 2021

- · Developed an app for renting of movies, CD's, DVD, received distinction grade. Full stack Java, Front end skills.
- · Developed a web and mobile variant of an application for an art gallery, featuring in-depth functionality backed by a hosted database.
- · Lead team project with 4 people to help develop a tool to solve a current problem in Ireland regard parking space.
- Courses Computing Programming, Data Communications, Computer Systems and Principles, Web Design, Operating Systems, Databases, Mobile Networking, Cloud Computing, Project Skills, System Analysis and Design, Virtualisation among others.

Experience

888 Spectate Dublin, Ireland

APPLICATION SUPPORT ENGINEER (LEVEL 2)

Dec 2021 - To Present

I oversee the web pages and functionalities of one of the biggest betting companies in Europe. Identifying issues while dealing with a vast database set and escalating it to the relevant departments after in depth investigation is at the core of my day-to-day

· Querying database

APRIL 20, 2022

- Monitoring of all production systems and sub-systems
- Ensuring effective front-end and back-end functionality of applications
- Documenting processes and monitoring application performance metrics
- Incident management, resolution and escalation of issues on all environments

SAR Security Dublin, Ireland

SECURITY OFFICER Feb 2017 - Nov 2021

I oversee one of the most valuable Art Studio in Europe/England at the Hugh Lane Gallery (Francis' Bacon Studio). In my role, I provide a safe environment for gallery Staff allowing both employees and more than 300 daily visitors to enjoy their time while on the Gallery premises.

- Checking visitor identification against a staff database.
- Conducting night patrols and inspections on the large premises.
- Watching over alarm systems and video cameras.
- Produce reports on daily activities and irregularities such as employee or visitor incidents and unusual occurrences.

Butlers Chocolate Dublin, Ireland

BARISTA Sep 2016 - Jan 2017

I worked in the Dundrum Shopping Centre unit which was an extremely fast-paced environment. I served around 3 thousand customers daily and produced nearly two drinks per customer so almost double. I provided excellent customer service by ensuring fast and efficient service at the tills. The best motivation was a satisfied customer. Having been complimented multiple times for having a smile on my face and making their experience really enjoyable.

- · Prepared and served hot and cold beverages such as coffee, espresso drinks, blended coffee, and teas.
- Managed daily rush of over 3 thousand customers with efficient, level-headed customer service.
- Maintained clear and organized workspace, enabling co-workers to locate resources and products.
- · Correctly followed all health, safety, and sanitation guidelines.
- · Greeted guests with pleasant smile and superior customer service.

Rodoviario Transbueno Ltda Guarulhos, Brazil

ADMINISTRATIVE ASSISTANT Feb 2010 - Mar 2016

As a Business Assistant for my company, I worked directly with the second largest Glue Manufacturer (Henkel) in the World. My company transported their raw material to thousands of companies around the country.

- Leveraging my business management and customer negotiation skills, I was able to secure the payment of a debt from our client to us of over 1 million reais (brazilian currency).
- Utilising my data driven and storytelling skills I produced daily reports covering over 200 deliveries that helped us improve efficiency. As a result we increased our income by 15% with the client in a month and 100% in a year.
- Ensured on time payments by implementing a process where I checked 500 daily reports and documents to identify any issues that could delay on time payments. As result, no delayed payments occurred for the time I was there.
- I have increased my responsibility starting as a Gate Clerk to Business Assistant. Assisting in the management of 3 branches as well as becoming a key person on customer relationships.

Skills

Database SQL

Microsoft Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Outlook, Windows 10, Windows Server

Programming Java, JavaScript, PHP

Web HTML5, CSS3

Languages English, Portuguese, Spanish

Qualifications Proactive, Business Strategy, Time management, Hard work, Focused, Driven, Analytic, Teamwork, Communicative, Adaptability,

Thrive in Challenges

Extracurricular Activities

Udemy Online

WEB DEVELOPER BOOTCAMP

- Due to my passion to learning coding and aim to become a professional Software Developer I am taking an extra course online to enhance my understanding of HTML, CSS3 and JavaScript.
- As well as learning how to creative responsive, accessible and beautiful layouts by using CSS frameworks including Bootstrap 5, semantic UI and Bulma.
- The course also provides a great understanding of HTML form with validations, how to manipulate DOM with vanila JS and how to use Postman to monitor DOM with vanilla JS.
- User authentication is also a paramount in the content and the knowledge of how to recognize and prevent common security exploits like SQL-Injection and XSS is also taught.

Volunteer at St Marks Church

MUSICIAN

- Showed leadership by guiding worship at services and carrying out meetings over zoom.
- · Guitar, singing